Right.
This is the moment you have been waiting for, because in a couple of seconds you are going to be a
programmer.
I know it's hard to believe that you're going to be a programmer literally in a few seconds.
So, Sarah, make them a programmer.
Okay, so obviously writing your first program is always an exciting experience.
I would actually have a camera out now and be capturing this moment.
You're a selfie moment because this is this is unbelievable.
Okay.
So let's get right into it.
So one of the most basic statements in programming is a statement called a print statement.
And it's pretty self-explanatory.
It prints it prints it prints.
So it's going to print something to your screen in order to use it.
Or we have to do is type and print.
And now we want to print something to our screen.
So we're going to print some text.
In order to print text you have to use quotation marks.
Now you'll notice that Sarah's typing wing is already recognizing what our Python command.
As soon as you type print you'll see a change color.
It's recognized this as a valid command, as is also recognized that those two little brackets that
Sara's put there were needed.
So if you hadn't have saved this file as dot p y, you'll notice that none of the colors will come out.
Everything will just be in black.
So you want to make sure that your things do have different colors, because then, you know wing is
recognizing it as a Python file.
Okay.
So the first program that almost all programmers will write is called Hello World.
So basically it's print and then in quotation marks hello world.
And then you can watch the grand moment drum roll.
Wow.
Your first program you've done it.
There it is at the bottom.
And this is where your displays are displayed.
So it's showing you what the output of the program hello world.
And that now makes you officially a programmer.
So well done.
At this point you can run around your house screaming, taking selfies, Instagram and share it.
Tell the world you're a programmer and it's as simple as that simple print statement that displays something
on your screen with an inverted commas.
You must put what that text is.
Obviously you could be a little more creative, but the classic first program for most programmers is
the Hello World one.
Okay, so now let's just make this a little bit more interesting.
We're going to add to our sentence.
So you can make the sentence as long as you want.
Really.
So instead of saying hello world I'm going to put my name and you can put your name.
So hello Sarah.
And you'll notice again it pops up here.
So this is our path in shell.
And any text or anything we print out using this print statement is going to come up inside this path
in shell.
Then we can print more than one lines if we'd like.
So we have our first statement which was hello, Sarah.
Okay, now let's say we want to type.
How are you?
Okay.
Now you'll see when we run our program, it's printed.
Hello, Sarah.
Then on the next line, it's printed.
How are you printing out two different print statements.
So it's as simple as that.
I mean, it couldn't be easier essentially, as we just said, you are a programmer, so come on, give
it a try.
Try some print statements.
It's a fun way to start, and it's just going to get more and more fun from here on out.